adtrustmedia.com 2017-12-30

# AdtrustMedia - Privacy Policy | We respect your Privacy

Effective Date: June 17, 2016

AdTrustMedia, LLC Privacy Policy

AdTrustMedia, LLC respects your privacy. We strive to use information to provide the best possible service while protecting the confidentiality of information we are entrusted with. This Privacy Policy outlines the types of personal information we may receive or collect when you use our services, as well as some of the methods used to safeguard personal information.

a. For End Users

When IP addresses of end users are received by AdTrustMedia, LLC, the geo- location data is stored and the IP address is discarded immediately. This is not considered personally identifiable information based on definitions in many jurisdictions. However, in some jurisdictions (such as California, U.S.A.), IP addresses or any identifier which allows an individual to be contacted electronically may be considered personal information. 

AdTrustMedia, LLC may also receive information and data such as URL’s visited, HTML headers, and geo-location data. All of this information and data is made anonymous and may be stored for up to six months. 

As a product connects to AdTrustMedia’s webservers to access the latest configuration details, IP addresses are automatically retrieved in webserver logs when the configuration files are accessed due to the nature of the webserver function. These webserver logs are deleted periodically. 

Additionally, in order to improve the performance, compatibility, and functionality of our products, AdTrustMedia may also collect computer identification; installed product version(s) and product identification; information on the computer operating system; information on any default browsers or browsers installed as well as extensions, add-ons, or plug-ins; installed software; install options, user consent, activity, use, and crash reports. 

Specific product collection and usage is provided below.

PrivDog (PC and DeskTop) Product:

The browsed URLs by you are not sent to AdTrustMedia, LLC. There are no advertisements shown to you and no information is collected from you.

PrivDog Browser Extension or Ad Sanitizer Product:

Any URLs browsed by you are sent to AdTrustMedia, LLC in order to show you relevant advertisements. Further, your user browsed URLs are sent to an ad server and are shared with affiliates to show you relevant advertisements. 

Users IP addresses are shared with affiliates to show relevant advertisements. 

Price Suggester Extension Product:

This product may send the URL you are browsing in supported browsers to the servers of AdTrustMedia, LLC to help show you relevant product price offers.

Browser Embedded Product Versions of Ad Sanitizer

Collection of End User information is as described under section 1(a) above.

b. For Advertisers/Publishers/User Owners:

Entity information is collected by AdTrustMedia, LLC in order to establish your account, to handle billing and to understand your specific needs to serve you better. Entity information is information about you that is identifiable, such as your entity name, address, email address, Tax ID or phone number.

AdTrustMedia, LLC may use cookies and other technologies to enhance your online experience and to learn about how you use our website and services. A “cookie” is a small file containing a string of characters that uniquely identifies your browser. While most browsers accept cookies by default, you can manually set your browser to refuse all cookies, accept cookies from specific websites, or highlight when a cookie is sent to your browser. AdTrustMedia, LLC’s servers may also automatically record information when you visit our website, including the URL that directed you to our website, your IP address, browser type and the date and time of your visit.

For End Users

PrivDog (PC and DeskTop) Product: 

No personal information of end users is collected. No cookies are used.

PrivDog Browser Extension or Ad Sanitizer Product: 

Cookies are used with this product. 

AdTrustMedia, LLC may send the URL you are browsing in supported browsers to the servers of AdTrustMedia, LLC to help show you relevant advertisements.

Price Suggester Extension Product:

Cookies are used for disabling this product.

The information collected is used to comprehensively understand your needs and interests, and permits AdTrustMedia, LLC to deliver a more consistent and personalized experience. For example, AdTrustMedia, LLC may use your information to: Provide promotional offers and display relevant advertisements. Improve performance, compatibility, and functionality. Your information may be aggregated with other clients’ information on a purely non- identifiable basis to understand how our products are used to help make them better.

AdTrustMedia, LLC shares URL’s visited, HTML headers, and geo-location data, in bulk or aggregate form, to third party affiliates. 

Circumstances may arise, whether for strategic or other business reasons, in which AdTrustMedia, LLC decides to sell, buy, merge or otherwise reorganize businesses in various countries. Such a transaction may involve the disclosure of personal information to prospective or actual purchasers, or, conversely, the receipt of such personal information from sellers. It is AdTrustMedia, LLC’s established practice to seek appropriate protection for all personal information in advance of any such transaction. 

We may have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to: (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or legitimate governmental request, (b) detect, prevent, or otherwise address suspected fraud, security or technical issues, (c) enforce any applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of AdTrustMedia, LLC its users or the general public as required or permitted by law.

The AdTrustMedia, LLC websites ([www.adtrustmedia.com](http://www.adtrustmedia.com/), and [www.privdog.com](http://www.privdog.com/)) may from time-to-time link to third-party websites for your convenience and to provide easy access to additional useful information. Should you select such a link, you will leave the AdTrustMedia, LLC website. AdTrustMedia, LLC does not control those sites nor their privacy practices, which may differ from AdTrustMedia, LLC’s practices and policies. Any personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by such third parties is not in any way covered by the AdTrustMedia, LLC Privacy Policy. It is recommended that you read over such website’s privacy policy before providing any personal information. A link to another website from AdTrustMedia, LLC websites does not constitute an endorsement or representation about the value, quality or usefulness of anything found on that third-party website. 

Further, our services and products may contain links to other third party websites, offers, ads or promotional material (together or in separate “Advertising Material”). Third party advertisers and/or merchants may collect information about you when you engage with such Advertising Material, including data pertaining to your use of and access to such advertiser’s sites, applications, services, and tools, and to help them personalize and improve your experience. Your engagement with any of such Advertising Material (and thus with third party advertisers and/or merchants) is made at your own risk and responsibility and is out of our control. We highly recommend you to carefully read those privacy policies of any provider of Advertising Material before any engagement you make with them. 

Information on specific AdTrustMedia, LLC products is provided below. 

1\. PrivDog (PC and Desk Top)

This product prevents advertisements from displaying on the Internet and websites you visit on the Internet by stopping communication with third party advertising network servers. If you do not wish to prevent the display of third party advertisements, do not install this product. 

The product also blocks widgets and blocks html elements from gathering user’s statistics and tracking user’s actions. It has no advertisement functionality.

2\. PrivDog Browser Extensions or Ad Sanitizer Products

Each of these products block and replace advertising networks. They each have an option for the user to switch the product to function as ad blocker only. These products also block widgets. In addition, the PrivDog Browser Extension blocks html elements from gathering user statistics and tracking user actions. 

The detailed disclosure of the Trusted Advertisements feature is below: 

THESE PRODUCTS PREVENT ADVERTISEMENTS FROM DISPLAYING ON THE INTERNET AND WEBSITES YOU VISIT ON THE INTERNET BY STOPPING COMMUNICATION WITH THIRD PARTY ADVERTISING NETWORK SERVERS. 

IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO PREVENT THE DISPLAY OF THIRD PARTY ADVERTISEMENTS, DO NOT INSTALL THESE PRODUCTS. 

THE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" FEATURE DISPLAYS ADVERTISEMENTS FROM A TRUSTED SOURCE IN THE EMPTY ADVERTISEMENT SECTIONS OF WEBPAGES WHERE ADVERTISEMENTS ARE PREVENTED FROM DISPLAYING ON THE USER’S COMPUTER BY THE PRODUCT. 

THE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" FEATURE ALSO OVERLAYS SEARCH RESULTS ADVERTISEMENTS WITH ADVERTISEMENTS FROM A TRUSTED SOURCE IN THE FORM OF AN OVERLAY WINDOW. THIS WINDOW IS IDENTIFIED BY DISCLOSURE OF AN "AT-M Ad" ON THE TOP LEFT OR RIGHT SECTION OF THE WINDOW. TO VIEW THE OTHER ADVERTISEMENTS UNDERNEATH THE TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS OVERLAY WINDOW AND CLOSE THE WINDOW, CLICK THE "See Non AT-M Ad" LINK PRESENT ON THE OVERLAY WINDOW. 

IF YOU ELECT TO RECEIVE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" WITH THE PRODUCT, YOU ARE GIVING EXPRESS PERMISSION TO ADTRUSTMEDIA TO SEND ADVERTISEMENTS TO YOU SOLEY FROM ADTRUSTMEDIA AND ITS AFFILIATES. THE ADVERTISEMENTS ARE DELIVERED TO YOU USING GEOLOCATION DATA OF YOUR COMPUTER. IF YOU DO NOT WISH TO RECEIVE ADVERTISEMENTS SOLELY FROM ADTRUSTMEDIA AND/OR ITS AFFILIATES, DO NOT SELECT THE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" OPTION. 

AFTER USING THE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" OPTION, IF YOU WISH TO TURN OFF THE "TRUSTED ADVERTISEMENTS" FEATURE, TAKE THE FOLLOWING STEPS:

a. Click on the PrivDog or AdSanitizer icon on the right side of the address bar of the browser.

b. In the drop down window, click the Settings icon.

Then, for AdSanitizer:

c. Clicking on the Settings icon takes you to Configurable options, select the "Protection" tab;

d. In the Protection tab you need to de-select "Deliver only safe ads from trusted ad sources" and ensure that the "Sanitize ads to protect my computer" radio box is selected.

Or for PrivDog:

c. Select the "Threats" tab;

d. In "threats" tab you need to select "Block all ad networks" radio button

b. Price Suggester Extension Product

The Price Suggester Extension Product is a price comparison web browser extension that activates itself on predefined shopping websites to bring better or alternative price options to users.

For End Users

AdTrustMedia, LLC collects information and data such as URL's visited, HTML headers, and geo-location data.

For Advertisers/Publishers/User Owners

We ask that you update your information as and when it changes so any information used to serve you remains as accurate as possible.

To prevent unauthorized access and disclosure, to maintain data accuracy, and to ensure the appropriate use of your information, AdTrustMedia, LLC utilizes industry standard physical, technical and administrative procedures to safeguard any personal information we may collect.

Information and/or data may be transferred to, and maintained on computers located outside of your state, province, country or other governmental jurisdiction where the privacy laws may not be as protective as those in your jurisdiction. 

For End Users

Your consent to this Privacy Policy, as represented by your continued use of the sites and/or the products, represents your agreement to this transfer of data and non-personally identifiable information. (such as URLs visited, HTML headers, geo-location data).

For Advertisers/Publishers /User Owners

If you are located outside the United States and choose to provide any personally- identifiable information to us, we may transfer your personally-identifying information to the United States and process it there. Your consent to this Privacy Policy, as represented by your continued use of the sites and/or the products, followed by your submission of any personally-identifying information represents your agreement to that transfer.

PrivDog (PC and Desk Top Version)

This product does not track users browsing the web and has no advertising functionality.

PrivDog Browser Extensions or Ad Sanitizer Products

If you do not wish to receive targeted advertisements, then while browsing the web, simply go to any webpage which shows an advertisement and follow the steps below.

1\. Click on the "AT-M Ad" inside the advertisement to open the "Ad Preferences" box.  
2\. Click "Ad Preferences" to go to https://adtrustmedia.com/prefs.html  
3\. Check the box next to: "I want to opt out of online behavior based ad targeting."

Note: You will still receive Trusted Advertisements, but the advertisements are not targeted based on your browsing pattern.

If you wish to block all advertisements for PrivDog, go to the product "Settings - Option," page and select the "Block all Ad Networks" radio button.

If you wish to block all advertisements for AdSanitizer, in the Protection tab, you need to de-select "deliver only safe ads from trusted as sources" and ensure that the "Sanitize ads to protect my computer" radio box is selected.

To turn off the Ad Sanitizer product, select the "Turn Off" button in the Protection tab.

Price Suggester Extension Product

This product does not track browsing history, so there is no opt out option from behavioral advertising needed. The specific URL of the page you are browsing may be sent to our servers to help show you relevant product price offers.

AdTrustMedia, LLC's products do not respond to a browser's "Do Not Track" signal. If you wish to opt out of advertisements due to any tracking, please see the Opt Out section above or use the PrivDog (PC and DeskTop) version only.

PrivDog (PC and DeskTop):

a. Go to "Add or Remove" on your operating system.  
b. Select or highlight the PrivDog or Ad Sanitizer program, then click "Remove."

PrivDog Browser Extension or Ad Sanitizer Products:

a. Go to "Add or Remove" on your operating system.  
b. Select or highlight the PrivDog or Ad Sanitizer program, then click “Remove.”

OR:

a. In the extensions section of a browser, select "Settings" and then go to "Extensions," select the PrivDog or Ad Sanitizer extension and then click on the Trash icon.

Price Suggester Extension Product :

a. Go to "Add or Remove" on your operating system.  
b. Select or highlight the Price Suggester Extension program, then click "Remove."

OR:

a. In the extensions section of a browser, select "Settings" and then go to "Extensions," select the Price Suggester extension product and then click on the Trash icon.

Our sites are not directed to children under the age of 13 and we do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If we become aware that a child under the age of 13 has provided us with personally identifying information, we will take steps to delete such information from our files as soon as possible.

If and when there are future changes to our Privacy Policy, in response we will post them at [www.adtrustmedia.com](http://www.adtrustmedia.com/) along with the Effective Date of the changes. We may also send you an email or other notification. Your continued use of the site(s) and/or products after we have notified you of any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

Please email us with any questions, concerns, opinions, or suggestions at [info@adtrustmedia.com](mailto:info@adtrustmedia.com), or alternately you can write to us at the following address:

AdTrustMedia, LLC  
41 Watchung Avenue  
Unit #330  
Montclair, NJ 07042
